所以我们已经看到了Python之间的一个关键区别
So we've seen that a key difference between the Python
Java代码是变量n有
and Java code is that the variable n has
表示它是int的类型声明。
a type declaration that says that it's an int.
我们这里没有明确显示的信息
We don't have that information explicitly displayed over here
在Python中，这是因为Java
in Python, and that's because Java
是一种静态类型语言。
is a statically typed language.
那这是什么意思？
So what does that mean?
这意味着所有变量的类型
That means that the types of all the variables
必须在程序运行之前知道。
have to be known before the program runs.
这就是静态的意思，基本上--
That's what static means, basically--
当程序在文件系统上静止时，在一个文件中
while the program is at rest on your file system, in a file
或者在编译时是另一种思考方式。
or at compile time is another way of thinking about it.
那是Java转换程序源代码的时候
That's when Java converts the program source
编码成可执行的形式。
code into an executable form.
所以这就是静态的意思，静态类型的
So that's what static means, and statically typed
意味着Java必须能够
means that Java has to be able to figure out
对于每个变量，每个表达式，确切地说
for every variable, every expression, exactly what
把它打出来。
type it's going to have.
所以对于变量
So for the variables you actually
必须明确地说n是int。
have to explicitly say n is an int.
对于表达式，编译器
For the expressions, the compiler
推导表达式的类型
deduces the type of the expression
通过观察其参数的类型。
by looking at the type of its arguments.
例如，如果编译器使用一个加号
So for example, if the compiler uses a plus
b和早些时候它看到a被声明为int
b and earlier it saw that a was declared as an int
b也被声明为int，然后它得出结论，
and that b was also declared as an int, then it concludes,
嗯，a加b也会是整数。
well, a plus b is also going to be an int.
所以Java，特别是Eclipse，会自动执行这个操作
So Java and, in particular, Eclipse do this automatically
当他们写代码的时候，会告诉你
while they're writing the code, and will tell you
当你还在的时候犯了类型错误
when you make type errors while you're still
输入代码——当你还在输入代码时，
typing the code-- while you're still entering the code,
我想是我该说的。
I suppose is what I should say.
与Python和JavaScript等语言相比，
Contrast that with languages like Python and JavaScript,
在某种意义上是动态类型的
which are dynamically typed, in the sense
你不知道n型有什么
that you don't find out what type n has
或者什么类型的表达式像a加b
or what type an expression like a plus b
在你真正运行程序之前
has until you are actually running the program
你遇到a加b，突然
and you come across a plus b, and suddenly you
发现a和b有不兼容的类型，
find that a and b have incompatible types,
你不能这么做，而且
and you can't do this plus, and that's
当Python出错时。
when Python would give you an error.
当您实际上
Java would give you an error about that when you actually
在程序编辑器中键入a和b。
typed a plus b into your program editor.
静态类型是一种特殊的类型
Now, static typing is a particular kind
一个叫做静态检查的概念
of a general idea called static checking, which
意味着在程序停止时检查错误，
means checking for bugs while the program is at rest,
在它开始运行之前。
before it starts running.
现在，bug从根本上说是编程的祸根。
Now, bugs are fundamentally the bane of programming.
你花在编程上的大部分时间，
Most of the time you spend in programming,
事实上，你花在寻找和修复错误上。
in fact, you spend looking for and fixing bugs.
这门课的很多想法
So many of the ideas in this course
旨在消除代码中的错误。
are aimed at eliminating bugs from your code.
几周后我们会有一个完整的阅读。
We'll have a whole reading about that in a few weeks.
但是静态检查是我们看到的第一个想法。
But static checking is the first idea that we've seen for this.
静态检查和静态类型
Static checking and static typing
防止一整类错误感染你的程序。
prevent a whole class of bugs from infecting your program.
对于静态类型，这些错误就是
For static typing, those bugs are the ones
对错误类型应用操作所导致的
that are caused by applying an operation to the wrong types
关于争论。
of arguments.
所以如果你读到一行这样的代码，
So if you read a broken line of code like this,
它试图将两个字符串相乘。
it's trying to multiply two strings together.
静态类型将捕获此错误
Static typing will catch this error
当你还在输入密码的时候，
while you're still entering the code,
而不是等到这条线
rather than waiting until this line is actually
在执行期间到达。
reached during execution.
所以概括起来，认为
So generalizing from that, it's useful to think
关于三种自动检测
about three kinds of automatic checking
一种编程语言可能会提供给我们。
that a programming language might provide us.
一种是静态检查
One kind is this static checking that we've just
一直在谈论在哪里会自动发现错误
been talking about where the bug is found automatically
在你开始之前。
before you even start the program.
另一个是动态检查
Another is dynamic checking, which
意思是当你到达那辆小车的地方
means that when you reach that buggy place-- let's
假设是这样的——编程
say it's something like this-- the programming
语言发现错误并通知您
language finds the error there and notifies you
关于这个错误。
about the error.
但是还有第三件事，有时编程
But then there's a third thing that sometimes programming
语言可以，但对你没有帮助
languages do, which is they don't help you
有了这个错误，事实上，
with the error at all and, in fact,
他们继续这样做，并产生了一个错误的答案。
they go ahead and execute this and produce a wrong answer.
然后你必须找出是什么导致了这个错误的答案。
And then you have to figure out what caused that wrong answer.
而那个错误的答案可能实际上
And that wrong answer might actually
在程序的其余部分传播。
propagate through the rest of your program.
直到很久很久以后你才会发现它。
And you won't discover it until much, much later.
然后你就遇到了调试的问题。
And then you have a problem with debugging.
所以在这种情况下
So it's situations where the language
不提供经常是最痛苦的错误的检查。
provides no checking that are often the most painful bug.
但总的来说，这里有等级制度。
But in general, there's a hierarchy here.
我们宁愿找出我们的虫子
We would much rather find out about our bugs
在我们开始之前。
before we even start the program.
如果不行，我们希望能找到他们
Failing that, we would like to be able to find them out
当程序运行时。
when the program is running.
这真是最糟糕的情况，
And this is really the worst case to be in,
因为这意味着你
because it means that you're having
你自己去找虫子。
to find the bug yourself.
你的编程语言也帮不了你。
And you're getting no help from your programming language.
下面是一些经验法则，可以用来判断哪些错误
Now here are some rules of thumb for what kinds of errors
Java将在不同的时间提供给您。
Java will give you at various times.
所以在Java之类的语言中进行静态检查
So static checking in languages like Java
会捕捉到语法错误，就像你加了额外的标点符号
will catch syntax errors, like if you put extra punctuation
或者在你的代码中加入一些虚假的词或其他东西，
or spurious words or something into your code,
在程序运行之前，甚至
then before the program even runs, even
对于像Python这样的动态类型语言，
for dynamically typed languages like Python,
你会犯错误的，或者你可能已经看到了，我相信，
you will get an error or you may have seen, I'm sure,
Python程序中的缩进错误。
indentation errors in your Python programs.
这些都是在程序运行之前报告的。
Those are reported before your program even starts running.
所以语法错误是一种静态检查
So syntax errors are a form of static checking
你已经从中受益了。
that you're already benefiting from.
Java提供的另一种静态检查
Another kind of static checking that Java provides
当你用错名字的时候。
is when you use the wrong name.
所以如果我试图调用sign函数并拼写它
So if I tried to call the sign function and spelled it
S-I-N-E，Java会在我
S-I-N-E, Java would tell me about this before I even
启动了程序。
started the program.
如果我给了那个函数错误的参数数目，
If I give the wrong number of arguments to that function,
它会告诉我的。
it will tell me about it.
如果我用错了类型，这就是我们已经讨论过的
If I use the wrong type, this is what we already talked about
静态输入。
with static typing.
如果我尝试传递字符串而不是浮点
If I try to pass a string instead of a floating point
数字，然后静态地得到一个错误。
number, then I'll get an error statically.
或者如果我试图从函数返回错误的类型，
Or if I try to return the wrong type from a function,
如果我返回试图返回的语句
if I return statement that tries to return
函数中的一个字符串，应该返回一个int，
a string from a function that's supposed to return an int,
然后Java会给我静态检查。
then Java will give me static checks.
所有这些都是静态错误
So all these things are static errors
只有像Java这样的静态类型语言
that only a statically typed language like Java
将提供。
will provide.
Python和JavaScript不会。
Python and JavaScript will not.
这些将在运行时发生。
These will happen at runtime.
将动态检查这些
These will be dynamically checked
通过Python和JavaScript。
by Python and JavaScript.
事实上，有些人，有趣的是这个，
In fact, some of them, interestingly this one,
甚至没有被JavaScript动态检查。
is not even checked dynamically by JavaScript.
幸运的是，Python做到了。
Fortunately, Python does.
所以这些都是Java
So these are all things that Java
可以通过查看您的代码
can figure out by looking at your code
甚至不运行它。
without even running it.
以下是一些Java无法解决的问题。
Here are some things that Java can't figure out.
如果参数值不合法，
So if there's an illegal argument value,
有一个值是类型的一部分，
there's a value that is part of a type,
但对于这个特殊的功能来说这实际上是不合法的，
but it's not actually legal for this particular function,
那么动态检查可以捕获它，但是静态检查不能。
then dynamic checking can catch it but static checking can't.
例如，除法对大多数整数来说都很好，
So for example, division is fine for most integers,
但如果y恰好是0，那么它将失败。
but if y happens to be 0, then it will fail.
现在，Java没有简单的方法
Now, there's no easy way for Java
在编译时找出这个表达式中的y
to figure out at compile time whether y in this expression
将为0。
will be 0.
所以这得等到
So this has to wait until it's actually
运行，直到它到达此表达式并看到y为0
running, until it reaches this expression and sees that y is 0
然后给你一个错误。
and then gives you an error.
另一个例子是不可表示的返回值。
Another example is unrepresentable return values.
例如，当特定的返回值不能
For example, when the specific return value can't actually
代表类型。
be representing the type.
你倾向于使用例外，我们将讨论
This you tend to use exceptions, which we'll talk
在几次阅读中。
about in a couple of readings.
另一个是超出范围的索引。
Another is out of range indexes.
例如，如果您试图索引到一个列表中
So for example, if you try to index into a list
或者在数组中使用负数
or into an array and you use a negative number
或者你用一个更大的数字
or you use a number that's larger
列表的大小或字符串的大小
than the size of the list or than the size of the string
那又会导致一个动态错误，
then that will cause a dynamic error, again,
因为同样的原因，你会得到动态错误
for the similar reason that you would get dynamic errors
用于非法参数值或调用方法
for illegal argument values or for calling a method
在空对象引用上。
on a null object reference.
我们稍后再谈null，
We'll talk more about null later,
但你可以认为它在Python中是没有的。
but you can think of it being like none in Python.
所以静态检查，一般的区别
So static checking, the general difference
在这两个类别之间，是静态检查
between these two categories, is static checking
倾向于类型。
tends to be about types.
所以那些独立于
So areas that are independent of specific
变量的值，但是
value that a variable has but that
对于该类型的每个值都将失败。
would fail for every value of that type.
而动态检查往往是关于
Whereas dynamic checking tends to be about particular
类型中的值。
values within a type.
现在，不幸的是，Java中有一个陷阱
Now, unfortunately, one trap in Java
是这些原始数字类型，如int和long
is that these primitive numeric types like int and long
浮子和双人有角盒
and float and double have corner cases that
不要表现得像数学上的整数
don't behave like the mathematical integers
以及我们很多人习惯的真实数字。
and real numbers that many of us are used to.
结果我们真的希望
And as a result some errors that we really wish
动态检查，换句话说，错误
were dynamically checked, in other words, errors
因为个人价值观，
that are due to individual values,
实际上根本没有被Java检查过，
aren't actually checked at all by Java,
这里有三个主要的陷阱。
and here are three of the major traps.
你可能已经在Python中遇到了第一个，
First one you may have already run into in Python,
尤其是在Python 2中编程的情况下。
particularly if you have programmed in Python 2.
Python 3实际上解决了这个问题。
Python 3 actually fixes this.
5除以2，音符返回一个分数，
5 divided by 2 does note return a fraction,
不返回2.5。
does not return 2.5.
因为5是一个整数，2是
What it does, because 5 is an integer and 2
是一个整数，它选择整数除法，
is an integer, this selects integer division,
这是一个返回整数的操作。
which is an operation that returns an integer.
它基本上是截短。
And what it does basically is it truncates.
它去掉了小数部分，所以5除以2
It eliminates the fractional part, so 5 divided by 2
将返回2。
will return 2.
这就是我们
So this is an example of where we
可能希望是——嗯，
might have hoped would be-- well,
我们可能希望得到正确的答案，也就是说，
we might have hoped we would get the correct answer, that is,
浮点数。
a floating point number.
但是，我们根本没有检查，
But instead, we get no checking at all,
我们得到了错误的答案。
and we get the wrong answer out of it.
第二类错误是整数溢出。
A second category of error is integer overflow.
所以int和long实际上是有限的整数集。
So int and long are actually finite sets of integers.
它们有最小值和最大值。
They have minimum and maximum values.
例如，Int上升到大约20亿正
Int, for example, goes up to about positive 2 billion
可以代表负20亿
and can represent about negative 2 billion
作为它的最小值。
as its smallest value.
这些数字看起来很庞大，但当计算机被关注时，
Those seem like big numbers, but when computers are concerned,
10亿不是一个大数字。
a billion is not a big number.
你可以很快计算出答案
And you can very quickly do a computation whose answer
远远大于最大的正数
is much greater than that largest positive number
或者比最小的负数小得多。
or much smaller than that smallest negative number.
那会发生什么呢？
So what happens?
不幸的是，在Java和许多编程语言中，
Unfortunately, in Java and in many programming languages,
计算悄悄地溢出。
that computation quietly overflows.
换言之，它会环绕并返回
In other words, it wraps around and returns
其他任意整数
some other arbitrary integer that
在法律规定的范围内
is somewhere in the legal range of int
但几乎可以肯定的是，计算结果的答案是错误的
but is almost certainly the wrong answer to the computation
你做到了。
that you did.
所以如果你想把20亿作为整数加到20亿
So if you try to add 2 billion as an int to 2 billion
作为智力，你不会得到40亿。
as an int, you will not get 4 billion.
你会得到一个很大的负数。
You'll get some large negative number.
第三类是浮点数。
And our third category are in the floating point numbers.
Float和double是两种浮点基元类型
Float and double are the two floating point primitive types
内置于Java中。
built into Java.
他们有几个特殊的价值观
They have several special values that
是IEEE浮点标准的一部分
are part of the IEEE floating point standard
但实际上不是真实的数字。
but aren't actually real numbers.
其中一个是这个值NAN，它不代表一个数字。
One of them is this value NAN, which stands for not a number.
另一个是正无穷大和负无穷大，
Another is positive infinity and negative infinity,
当你除以0时会发生这种情况。
which can happen when you divide by 0.
所以有些手术你会
So some operations that you would
预计会出现动态错误
expect you would get dynamic errors and that actually do
执行时给出动态错误
give dynamic errors when you do them
如果你除以0，
with other kinds of numbers, so if you divide by 0,
如果你使用int，你会得到一个异常。
and you're using ints, you will get an exception.
你将得到一个错误，你的程序将停止。
You'll get an error, and your program will stop.
相反，对于浮点数，
Instead, with floating point numbers,
你会得到一个特殊的值，
you will get one of these special values,
计算将继续。
and the computation will continue.
如果你继续计算，
And if you keep computing with it,
你最终会得到一个糟糕的答案。
you'll end up with some kind of bad final answer.
所以这些陷阱告诉我们为什么
So these are traps that show us why
静态检查和动态检查
static checking and dynamic checking
比没有支票更有价值。
can be much more valuable than no checking.